### DATA SCIENTIST · COMPUTER SCIENTIST

Girona, Spain

👼 wilberquito | in wilberquito | ⊠ typingwil@gmail.com | 🛛 (+34) 698-40-53-59 | 💣 wilberquito.github.io

"The best way to predict the future is to create it."

#### About Me

I'm a Computer Science graduate with a specialization in Data Science and Machine Learning, bringing over three years of experience in IT solutions. I started as a Software Developer, but my passion for data-driven insights led me to focus on Machine Learning. Outside of my professional life, I stay active through physical activities and enjoy developing personal projects, such as video game development and blogging about math and technology.

### **Education**

University of Girona Girona Girona

MSc. in Data Science 🗞

 Studies focused on advanced skills in analyzing and deriving insights from data using statistical and machine learning methods.

University of Girona Girona, Spain

Jun. 2022

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

BEng. in Computer Science 🗞

• I take pride in my accomplishment of attaining excellence in the final degree project, which entailed the creation of an open-source video game.

## **Work Experience**

Associate Assistant Professor

multiple databases.

**Citibeats**Barcelona, Spain

Data Scientist Sep. 2023 - Mar. 2024

- Developed topic modeling pipelines with large language models (LLMs) such as BERT and Sentence Transformers.
- Improved explainability using unsupervised learning techniques like clustering and model-based feature extraction.
- Conducted research and implemented rapid experiments, thoroughly documenting the process for reproducibility and results.
- Developed private Python libraries, created web-hook services, and deployed trained models in private repositories.
- Provided technical support for previous company projects, including fixing bugs, adding features, refitting and fine tuning models.

University of Girona Girona Girona

• My responsibilities included overseeing lab sessions in order to instruct students in functional and logic

programming, correct lab projects, and supervise exams.

Accenture SL GIRONA, SPAIN

Computer Vision Research Dec. 2022 - Aug. 2023

 Developed and open-sourced a Computer-Aided Diagnosis (CAD) platform using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) for detecting melanoma.

# Nexus GeographicsGIRONA, SPAINData EngineerSep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

• Significantly contributed to the development of a concurrent framework designed to capture, map, and store data from diverse sources.

- Created and manteined API micro-services to injest and serve data. Ensuring data consistency across
- Designed and developed interactive web applications to visualize on-demand and streaming data.
- Provided training to new team members on the primary technologies utilized in the projects and offered problem-solving support.

WILBER BERMEO QUITO · CURRICULUM VITAE

NexTReT Girona, Spain

Software Engineer Abr. 2020 - Sep. 2021

- Designed and developed a wide range of Restful APIs.
- Created interactive web applications for the healthcare sector, taking responsibility for building modules including authentication, hospital bed administration, external hospital services, and more.

### Tech Skills\_

Workflow Conda, Git, GitHub, Jupyter Notebook, Linux, Vim
Frameworks Angular, FastAPI, Flask, Spring Boot, Svelte
MLOps / DevOps Docker, GitHub Actions, MLflow, W&B

ML & Data Tools Hugging Face, Kafka, Pandas, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, SQL

**Cloud Computing** Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Colab **Programming Languages** C++, Java, JS, Python, Shell Scripting, Scala, R

### Other Skills of Interest

**Languages** English (C1), Spanish (Native) and Catalan (Bilingual)

**Driver's License** B

## **Certificates**

2023 Prevention & Emergency Management, Co-funded by the Erasmus+ Programme of the European Union

2022 Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark, Udemy

2022 Advanced Machine Learning, Kaggle

2022 Advanced SQL, Kaggle

2021 Advanced Functional Programming (FP), University of Helsinki

### References\_

PROF. DR. MATEU VILLARET 
PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA
MATEU.VILLARET@UDG.EDU

PROF. DR. GUSTAVO PATOW 
PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA
GUSTAVO.PATOW@UDG.EDU

QUIM DALMAU **S**TECH LEAD AT CITIBEATS
JDALMAUT@GMAIL.COM